我又开始考虑时光旅行的事了
You know, I've been thinking about time travel again.
为什么?  你撞上看不见的障碍物了?
Why? did you hit a roadblock with invisibility?
先不提那个
Put it on a backburner.
不论如何  我突然想到
Anyway. it occurs to me,
如果我能有个完美的时光机
If I have ever did perfect time machine,
我就能回到过去  把它送给当时的我
I'd just go into the past and give it to myself.
那样我就不用现做一个了
That's eliminating the need for me to invent it in the first place.
有意思
Interesting.
这确实能消除压力
Yeah, it really kicks the pressure off.
听起来是个新突破
Sounds like a breakthrough.
要不要我打电话到科学期刊 让你上封面?
Should I call science magazine and tell them to hold the cover?
这可是时光旅行  我应该早就上封面了
It's time travel, I will have already done that.
那我想接下来我该恭喜你了
Then I guess congratulations are in order.
不  那时你应该已经恭喜过了
No, congratulations will have been in order.
你知道  我不会喜欢这个派对的
You know, I am not going to enjoy this party.
我知道  我太了解你了
I know, I'm familiar with you.
上次系里聚会  芬克顿教授缠着我
The last department party, professor Finkleday cornered me
一直和我探讨洞穴探险  谈了45分钟
And talked about spelunking for 45 minutes.
没错  我也在那儿
Yes, I was there.
你知道洞穴有什么意思吗?
You know what's interesting about caves?
-什么?  -什么都没有
-what? -nothing.
那么我们就避开他  去见新的系主任
Then we'll avoid him, we'll meet the new department head,
向他道喜  和他握手  然后离开
Congratulate him, shake his hand and go.
这样说如何?  很高兴见到您  盖博豪斯博士
How's this? "pleased to meet you, dr. gablehauser.
你真走运  学校选了你做系主任
"how fortunate for you that the university's
尽管事实上
"chosen to hire you, despite the fact
25年里您从未有过原创性的研究
"that you've done no original research in 25 years,
仅仅出版了一系列畅销书
"and instead have written a series of popular books
把伟大的科技理念
"that reduce the great concepts of science
贬低成了一连串的奇闻异事
"to a series of anecdotes,
那些故事烂到刚好可以
"each one dumbed down to accommodate the duration
供我们上厕所的时候消遣一下
"of an average bowel movement.
谢谢(夏威夷语)
Mahalo."
谢谢这个词加的不错
"mahalo's" a nice touch.
你知道夏威夷语只有8个辅音吗
You know there only eight consonants in hawaiian language?
有意思  你该好好研究一下那个
Interesting. you should lead with that.
天啊  看看这个自助
Oh, god, look at this buffet.
我爱美国
I love america.
印度没有自助吗
You don't have buffets in india?
当然有  但都是印度食物
Of course, but it's all indian food.
在孟买连个救命的面包圈都找不到
You can't find a bagel in mumbai to save your life.
帮我抹一下
Shmear me.
-这回有趣了  -什么?
-here's an interesting turn of events. -what?
霍华德带了个女伴?
Howard brought a date?
更可信的解释是
A more plausible explanation is that
他的机器人学研究
His work in robotics has made
取得了质的飞跃
An amazing leap forward.
你们好啊  科学婊子们?
Hey, what up, science bitches?
请允许我向你们介绍
May I introduce my
我的特别女伴夏末
Special lady friend summer?
-我说过身体接触要另外付费  -好  对不起
-i told you touching's extra. -right. sorry.
我们的新老板来了  礼貌一点
Here comes our new boss. be polite.
嗨  伙计们  艾瑞克·盖博豪斯
Hi, fellas. eric gablehauser.
霍华德·沃尔维茨
Howard Wolowitz.
很高兴见到你  你是?
Nice to meet you. and you are?
一个真真正正的科学家
An actual real scientist.
这样如何?
How was that?
真不敢相信他把我炒了
I can't believe he fired me.
谁让你说他只是个名声显赫的高中理科老师
Well, you did call him a glorified high school science teacher
还说他最近成功的实验只是放屁
Whose last successful experiment was lighting his own farts.
我要为自己辩护一下
In my defense,
我一开始就说了  恕我冒昧
I prefaced that by saying, "with all due respect."
早上好
Morning.
你打算早餐吃鸡蛋?
You're making eggs for breakfast?
这不是早餐  这是个实验
This isn't breakfast, it's an experiment.
那看起来很像是早餐
Cause it looks a lot like breakfast.
我终于有时间验证我的假设
I finally have time to test my hypothesis
看看水分子从鸡蛋的蛋白质中分离出来
About the separation of the water molecules
是否对口感有影响
From the egg proteins and its impact vis-a-vis taste.
听起来很好吃
Sounds yummy.
我期待你用火腿做实验
I look forward to your work with bacon.
我也是
As do i.
我相信只要你跟
You know, I'm sure if you just apologize
盖博豪斯道歉  他会让你复职的
To gablehauser, he would give you your job back.
我不想复职
I don't want my job back.
我过去3年半都一直
I've spent the past three and a half years
盯着写满等式的黑板
Staring at grease boards full of equations.
那之前  我花了4年完成我的论文
Before that, I spent four years working on my thesis.
再之前  我在上大学
Before that, I was in college,
再再之前  我上5年级
And before that, I was in the fifth grade.
这是我十年来第一个休息日  我要好好享受
This is my first day off in decades and I'm going to savor it.
那你好好研究你的鸡蛋理论吧
I'll let you get back to fixing your eggs.
不只是我的鸡蛋  是大家的鸡蛋
Not just fixing my eggs, I'm fixing everyone's eggs.
我们都感谢你
And we all thank you.
用了新的鸡蛋
Use new eggs.
我要去超市  你们需要什么吗
I'm running out to the market. you need anything?
这应该属于那种
This would be one of those circumstances
不熟悉大数法则的人称之为
That people unfamiliar with the law of large numbers would call a
"巧合"的情况
Coincidence.
-你说什么?  -我要买鸡蛋
-i'm sorry? -i need eggs.
4打应该够了
Four dozen should suffice.
-4打?  -没错
-four dozen? -yes,
要棕色皮的  白皮的
And evenly distributed amongst brown, white,
无公害的  大的  特大个的  巨蛋各几个
Free-range, large, extra large and jumbo.
好吧  再说一次
Okay, one more time.
没关系  你估计弄不对
Never mind. you won't get it right.
我最好和你一起去
I'd better come with you.
你今天怎么没去上班?
How come you didn't go into work today?
我现在休假
I'm taking a sabbatical
因为我不要对那种俗人低三下四
Because I won't kowtow to mediocre minds.
所以你被解雇了  对吗
So you got canned, huh?
理论物理学家不会被炒鱿鱼的...
Theoretical physicists do not get canned...
但是确实是被炒了
But yeah.
也许那样更好呢
Maybe it's all for the best.
我一直说一扇门关上的同时  另一扇门也已打开
I always say when one door closes, another one opens.
不  不是那样的
No, it doesn't.
除非那两扇门有继电器
Not unless the two doors are connected by relays
-或者感应器连着  -不  我是说...
-or there are motion sensors involved. -no, I meant...
否则第一扇门关上造成的气压变化
Or if the first door closing creates a change of air pressure
会带动第二扇门也关上
That acts upon the second door.
算了
Never mind.
慢一点
Slow down.
-求你了  慢一点  -没事的
-please, slow down! -we're fine!
你离前面的车距离太近了
You're not leaving yourself enough space between cars.
-当然  我知道  -不行  我给你算算
-oh, sure, I am. -no, let me do the math for you.
这个车重  就算是4000磅
This car weighs, let's say 4,000 pounds.
然后加上我的重量140磅  你的120磅...
Now add 140 for me, 120 for you...
120?
对不起  我有冒犯到你吗
I'm sorry. did I insult you?
你的体重跟你的个人价值有关么?
Is your body mass somehow tied into your self-worth?
是的
Well, yeah.
有意思
Interesting.
不管怎么说  总共就算是
Anyway, that gives us a total weight of,
就算是4400磅
Let's say 4,400 pounds.
算4390磅吧
Let's say 4,390.
好吧  我们行驶时速是
Fine. we're traveling forward at--
天啊  51英里每小时
Good lord--51 miles an hour.
假设你的刹车是新的
Let's assume that your brakes
卡钳(刹车系统的一部分)在一条线上
Are new and the calipers are aligned.
然而  到我们要停下来的时候
Still, by the time we come to a stop,
我们会和前面的别克撞到一起
We'll be occupying the same space as that buick in front of us,
不过致死  致残
An impossibility that nature will quickly resolve
倒是不可能的
Into death, mutilation...
看  他们修了一个新的高尔夫球场
Oh, look, they built a new putt-putt course.
太伟大了
This is great.
看着我
Look at me.
我活在一个凡人生活的
I'm in the real world of ordinary people
真实的世界里  无聊的上班一族
Just living their ordinary, colorless workaday lives.
谢谢你
Thank you.
不  谢谢你
No, thankyou.
也谢谢你  平凡的人
And thank you, ordinary person.
你想听听关于西红柿的有趣的事吗
You want to hear an interesting thing about tomatoes?
不  我不太想
No, not really.
你不是说你要买鸡蛋吗
Listen, didn't you say you need some eggs?
是的  但是有谁知道细菌
Yes, but anyone who knows anything about the dynamics of bacterial growth
就是冷冻食品在离开超市的途中
Knows to pick up their refrigerated food on the way out of the
迅速繁殖的
Supermarket.
好吧  也许你该想办法解决一下
Okay, then maybe you should start heading on out then.
不 这很有趣
No, this is fun.
关于西红柿的是...我想你会喜欢的
Oh, the thing about tomatoes-- and I think you'll really enjoy this--
虽然摆在蔬菜架上  但理论上讲是水果
Is they're shelved with the vegetables, but they're technically a fruit.
-有意思  -真的吗
-interesting. -isn't it?
不  我是说你自得其乐
No, I mean what you find enjoyable.
孩子
Oh, boy.
又怎么了?
What now?
吃多种维生素是有很多好处
Well, there's some value to taking a multivitamin,
但是人只能吸收一定的量
But the human body can only absorb so much.
所以你买这么多
What you're buying here
就是买一堆贵重的尿的原料
Are the ingredients for very expensive urine.
也许那就是我想要的
Well, maybe that's what I was going for.
那你就该买些锰
Then you'll want some manganese.
这很有意思
That was fun.
也许明天我们可以去大仓储商店转转
Maybe tomorrow we can go to one of those big warehouse stores.
我没想好
Oh, I don't know.
也许我得花点时间消化今天的玩笑
It's going to take me a while to recover from all the fun I had today.
你确定?
Are you sure?
成批购买有很多好处的
There are a lot of advantages to buying in bulk.
比如说  我注意到你买卫生巾
For example, I noticed that you purchase your tampons
都是一次买一个月量的
One-month supply at a time.
什么?
What?
你考虑一下吧  那东西也放不坏
Think about it. it's a product that doesn't spoil
而且你至少还要用30年
And you're going to be needing them for at least the next 30 years.
你想让我一次买够30年用的?
You want me to buy 30 years worth of tampons?
30  35  你妈妈什么时候到更年期的?
Well, 30, 35. when did your mother go into menopause?
我不想现在和你谈这个
I'm not talking about this with you.
这是很自然的人生过程
This is a natural human process,
而且我们说的是怎么省钱的问题
And we're talking about statistically significant savings.
假设你一周期用15包卫生巾  28天一周期
Now, if you assume 15 tampons per cycle and a 28-day cycle...
你是定期来吗
Are you fairly regular?
那好吧  不去大仓储商店了
Okay, no warehouse store,
但我们还要去打高尔夫  好吗
But we're still on for putt-putt golf, right?
我遇到潘妮  她好像有些不高兴
Hey, I just ran into penny. she seemed upset about something.
我想她生理期到了
I think it's her time of the month.
以防以后要查  我在日历上标出来了
I marked the calendar for future reference.
这鱼是怎么回事?
What's with the fish?
我在做实验
It's an experiment.
那个炒鸡蛋研究怎么样了?
What happened to your scrambled egg research?
死路一条
Oh, that was a dead end.
炒鸡蛋怎么弄都一样
Scrambled eggs are as good as they're ever going to be.
那么...就研究鱼了?
So... fish?
我读过一篇关于日本科学家们的文章
I read an article about japanese scientists
把发光的水母的基因植入其他动物体内
Who inserted dna from luminous jellyfish into other animals,
那么我想  夜光鱼
And I thought, "hey, fish nightlights."
夜光鱼?
Fish nightlights?
这主意能值一百万
It's a billion-dollar idea.
我不会说出去的
Mum's the word.
你确定不要向
Are you sure you don't want
盖博豪斯道歉  回去工作?
To just apologize to gablehauser and get your job back?
不去  我还有好多事要做
No, I have too much to do.
比如会发光的鱼
Like luminous fish.
对不起  我没有...
I'm sorry. I didn't...
这只是刚刚开始
That's just the beginning.
我还有一个好主意
I also have an idea
开一个批量邮购妇女卫生用品公司
For a bulk mail-order feminine hygiene company.
夜光卫生巾
Oh, glow-in-the-dark tampons!
里奥纳德  我们要发财了
Leonard, we're gonna be rich.
谢谢您匆忙赶来
Thanks for coming on such short notice.
-你做的很对  -我不知道还能做什么
-you did the right thing calling. -i didn't know what else to do.
他迷失方向了  每天都沉迷于新想法
He's lost all focus. every day he's got a new obsession.
这个尤其让人困扰
This is a particularly disturbing one.
妈?
Mommy?
嗨  宝贝
Hi, baby!
你把我妈叫来了(口型)
You called my mother
你怎么在织布?  太漂亮了
Oh, you got yourself a loom? how nice!
谢谢
Thank you.
亲爱的  你为什么要织布?
Honey, why'd you get a loom?
我正在研究会发光的鱼  然后我想...
I was working with luminous fish, and I thought...
织布机
"loom."
妈  你怎么来了?
Mom, what are you doing here?
里奥纳德打电话叫我来的
Leonard called me.
我知道  但是为什么?
I know, but why?
因为21世纪伟大的天才之一
Because one of the great minds of the 21st century
要养会发光的鱼  还要织披肩
Is raising glow-in-the-dark fish and weaving serapes.
这不是披肩  这是披风
This is not a serape, this is a poncho.
披肩在两边都是开着的  披风是一体的
A serape is open at the sides; a poncho is closed.
这是披风
This is a poncho.
不管是什么你都不该把我妈叫来
And neither is a reason to call someone'smother.
真的?  你上次出门是什么时候?
Really? when was the last time you left the house?
我和潘妮一起去超市
I went to the market with penny.
那都是3个星期以前的事了
That was three weeks ago.
然后就没出去过  后来的4到8天
Well, then buckle up. in the next four to eight days
她变得异常暴躁
She's going to get very crabby.
亲爱的  你的小朋友在关心你
Sweetheart, your little friend is concerned about you.
是的  但我不是孩子了  我是大人了
Yes, well, I'm not a child-- I'm a grown man,
我的生活我自己做主
Capable of living my life as I see fit.
而且我绝对不需要某人通知我妈妈
And I certainly don't need someone telling on me to my mother!
等等  你去哪儿?
Wait, where are you going?
回我屋里  谁都不许进来
To my room. and no one's allowed in!
他这脾气遗传自他爸爸
He gets his temper from his daddy.
我老得盯着他
He's got my eyes.
我明白
I see.
所有科学的东西  都来自耶稣
All that science stuff, that comes from jesus.
-谢尔顿  你妈做了晚餐  -我不饿
-sheldon, your mom made dinner. -i'm not hungry!
别理他  他很拗
Don't trouble yourself. he's stubborn.
他会一直待到他满意为止
He may stay in there till the rapture.
这一定不好么?
We so sure that's a bad thing?
我跟你们说  我非常爱这个孩子
I tell you, I love the boy to death,
但自从他在k-mart和我吵过后就很难对付了
But he has been difficult since he fell out of me at the k-mart.
请原谅我这么说
Excuse me for being so bold,
但是我看出来谢尔顿的帅气遗传自谁了
But I now see where sheldon gets his smoldering good looks.
亲爱的  这可不对  但继续努力吧
Honey, that ain't gonna work, but you keep tryin'.
我做了鸡
I made chicken.
我希望你们那的人不会把它当神物
I hope that isn't one of the animals that you people think is magic.
我们那的教堂有一个印度绅士
You know, we have an indian gentleman at our church,
派特博士  那是个很美的故事
A dr. patel-- it's a beautiful story.
上帝告诉他  让他给我们20%的折扣
The lord spoke to him and moved him to give us all 20% off on lasik--
我们很需要的
You know, those that needed it.
那是个很棒的故事
That is a lovely story.
我们就放着谢尔顿不管吗
Are we gonna do anything about sheldon?
我们要管  你们对谢尔顿要慢慢来
Oh, we will. you have to take your time with sheldon.
他爸爸  上帝保佑他  常常对我说
His father, god rest his soul, used to always say to me,
玛丽  对谢尔顿要慢慢来
"mary, you have to take your time with sheldon."
-听起来像个哲人  -还不够聪明
-sounds like a wise man. -oh, not so wise.
他曾经和一只山猫争一些甘草
He once tried to fight a bobcat for some licorice.
那么  每个人都有一个盘子了
So, everybody grab a plate
以及一块"谢莉"织的漂亮垫布
And a pretty place mat that shelly wove.
"谢莉"以前也这样发过狂么?
Has shelly ever freaked out like this before?
一直都是这样
Oh, all the time.
我记得一年夏天  那时他13岁
I remember one summer when he was 13,
他在车库建了一个小型的核反应堆
He built a small nuclear reactor in the shed
告诉大家他要为整个镇子
And told everybody he was gonna provide free electricity for the whole
免费供电
Town.
唯一的问题是
Well, the only problem was,
他没有那种你们称之为可裂变的物质
He had no what you call "fissionable" materials.
但他到网上去搞的时候
Anyway, when he went on the internets to get some,
政府的人知道了  就来找他
A man from the government came by and sat him down
非常绅士  然后告诉他
Real gentle, and told him it's against the law
车库里存放黄饼(铀的化学浓缩物)是违法的
To have yellow-cake uranium in a shed.
-后来呢?  -可怜的孩子大发脾气
-what happened? -well, poor boy had a fit.
把自己锁在屋里  弄声波杀伤性射线
Locked himself in his room and built a sonic death ray.
声波杀伤性射线?
A death ray?
他自己叫的  都不能让邻居孩子慢下来
That's what he called it. didn't even slow down the neighbor kids.
连让狗滚开都不成
It pissed our dog off to no end.
你们两个像是一对可爱的情侣
You know, you two make a cute couple.
不  我们不是...我们不是情侣
No. we're not... we're not-not a couple.
我们都是单身  两个单身
We're singles. two singles.
就像那些...独立包装的奶酪...
Like those... individuly wrapped slices of cheese that...
我们只是朋友
We're friends.
-我的话是不是让他们紧张了?  -没错
-did I pluck a nerve there? -oh, yeah.
好吧  各位  让我们开动吧
All right, everybody, it's time to eat.
上帝啊  谢谢你赐予我们这顿晚餐
Oh, lord, we thank you for this meal
以及你的慷慨
And all of your bounty.
我们祈求你帮谢尔顿
And we pray that you help sheldon
回到他的人生正途
Get back on his rocker.
现在  默念之后
Now, after a moment of silent meditation,
我会说"看在上帝的份上"作为结束
I'm gonna end with "in jesus' name,"
但是你们可以不必加入
But you two don't feel any obligation to join in.
当然  除非  圣灵降临到你们身上
Unless, of course, the holy spirit moves you.
天啊  这是我吃过的最棒的水果派
Oh, my god, this is the best cobbler I've ever had.
这是谢尔顿的最爱
It was always sheldon's favorite.
你知道秘方是什么吗
You know what the secret ingredient is?
-爱?  -猪油
-love? -lard.
看谁来了...
Hey, look who's come...
你会吓着他的
You'll spook him.
他就像个小鹿  你要让他来接近你
He's like a baby deer. you got to let him come to you.
太荒唐了  他妈的  谢尔顿  振作起来
This is ridiculous. damn it, sheldon, snap out of it!
你是个物理学者
You're a physicist--
你该在大学里做研究  而不是躲在屋子里
You belong at the university doing research, not hiding in your room!
你没抓到他  对吧?
You don't hunt, do you?
早上好  小傻瓜
Good morning, snickerdoodle.
早上好
Morning.
那个看来很糟糕的东西是什么?
Well, that looks awful fancy. what is that?
是我想象基因在
It's my idea of what dna would look like
硅化生命中的形态
In a silicon-based life-form.
但这模型是机器自动造出来的是吧?
But intelligently designed by a creator, right?
你想干什么  妈妈?
What do you want, mom?
你爸爸常说  人钓鱼也就那么点耐性
You know how your daddy used to say that you can only fish for so long
钓了一会就恨不得扔一堆炸药下去
Before you got to throw a stick of dynamite in the water?
现在  我钓鱼钓够了
Well, I'm done fishing.
换上这些
You put those on.
-干什么?  -去办公室
-what for? -because you're gonna
向你的老板道歉
Go down to your office, you're gonna apologize
回去工作
To your boss and get your job back.
-不  -抱歉
No. I'm sorry,
你是想要我说
Did I start that sentence with the words,
请问殿下?
"if it please your highness"?
我不要去道歉  我说的都是事实
I'm not going to apologize-- I didn't say anything that wasn't true.
听着
Now, you listen here.
我从你4岁就告诉你
I have been telling you since you were four years old,
比别人聪明可以接受
It's okay to be smarter than everybody,
但你不能一直强调这点
But you can't go around pointing it out.
-为什么不能?  -因为人们不爱听
-why not? -because people don't like it!
忘了当年你怎么被邻居家孩子欺负的?
Remember all the ass-kickings you got from the neighbor kids?
现在  快点
Now, let's get crackin'.
洗澡  换衬衫  鞋子  然后我们出发
Shower, shirt, shoes, and let's shove off.
如果那个该死的声波杀伤射线
There wouldn't have been any ass-kickings
管用的话  我就不会挨打
If that stupid death ray had worked.
问题解决
Problem solved.
真的?  太好了
Really? that's impressive.
里奥纳德  上帝从不会给我们太多
Leonard, the lord never gives us more than we can handle.
幸运的是  他让我另外两个孩子
Thankfully, he blessed me with two other children
笨的可以
Who are dumb as soup.
打扰一下  盖博豪斯博士  你现在忙吗
Excuse me, dr. gablehauser, are you busy?
-事实上...  -谢尔顿  他正瞎画呢
-well, actually... -sheldon, he's just doodlin'.
进来
Get in here.
开始吧  宝贝儿  我们没那么多时间
Let's go, baby. we're losing daylight.
你知道
As you know,
几周前  我们初次见面
Several weeks ago in our first encounter,
当我叫你是傻瓜时
We may have gotten off on the wrong foot
我们可能一开始就没看对眼
When I called you an idiot.
我只是想说我不该...
And I just wanted to say that I was wrong...
把那点指出来
To point it out.
很抱歉  我们还没有相互介绍
I'm sorry, we haven't been introduced.
谢尔顿的妈妈
Sheldon's mom.
真没想到  你生他的时候肯定只有十几岁
Now, that's impossible! you must have had him when you were a teenager.
你真会说话  他爸爸死了
Oh, aren't you sweet. his father's dead.
-最近吗   -很久以前了
-recently? -long enough.
请坐
Please.
谢尔顿  你不用去工作吗
Sheldon, shouldn't you be working?
嘿  怎么样?
Hey, how did it go?
我复职了
I got my job back.
真的?  怎么回事?
Really? what happened?
我也不太清楚
I'm not quite sure.
这牵扯到一些一直困惑着我的
It involves a part of the human experience
人生经历
That has always eluded me.
这个范围就小了
That narrows it down.
我很为你骄傲  亲爱的
I'm very proud of you honey.
你今天很勇敢
You showed a lot of courage today.
谢谢  妈妈
Thanks, mom.
盖博豪斯博士要当我的新爸爸了吗
Is dr. gablehauser going to be my new daddy?
再看吧
We'll see.
睡个好觉
Sleep tight.